John R. Murdock papers, 1937-1952
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
John R. Murdock papers, 1937-1952
AZ 151
Murdock, John Robert
Correspondence, records of committee meetings, bills, hearings, reports, clippings, reprints of Murdock's remarks in Congress, printed and typescript material relating chiefly to the Colorado River and the water rights for Arizona including the Central Arizona Project, the Gila Project, and the proposed Bridge Canyon Dam. Also included are drafts of articles on political questions; newspaper clippings concerning his wife, Myrtle; and correspondence relating to the death of his son, David, in World War II.
.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
U.S. Representative from Arizona, 1936-1953.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Personal Materials, 1937-1952
Series II: Congressional Papers, 1938-1952
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, records of committee meetings, bills, hearings, reports, clippings, reprints of Murdock's remarks in Congress, printed and typescript material relating chiefly to the Colorado River and the water rights for Arizona including the Central Arizona Project, the Gila Project, and the proposed Bridge Canyon Dam. Also included are drafts of articles on political questions; newspaper clippings concerning his wife, Myrtle; and correspondence relating to the death of his son, David, in World War II.
Access Terms
Murdock, John Robert -- 1885-1972
Murdock, David Nathaniel
Murdock, Myrtle Cheney
Gila Project (U.S.)
Central Arizona Project
Legislators -- Arizona
Water supply -- Arizona
Water power -- Arizona
Water resources development -- Arizona
Bridges -- Colorado River (Colo.-Mexico)
Arizona -- Politics and government -- 20th century
United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century
Colorado River (Colo.-Mexico) -- Water rights
Bridge Canyon Dam (Ariz.: proposed)
Correspondence
Speeches
Bills (legislative)
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Personal Materials, 1937-1952
  - Articles, Speeches, Reminiscences, etc. (typescripts; includes radio addresses and transcripts of tapes). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence. 1938-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Material (includes material on son David N. Murdock and wife Mrytle Cheney Murdock.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - News Paper Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Congress: Remarks and Speeches by JRM. 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Congress: Bills and Resolutions Sponsored by JRM. 1939-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Congress: Committee on Public Lands, Subcommittee on Irrigation & Reclamation, Hearings. 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Congress: Various Committees, Hearings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Congressional Papers, 1938-1952
  - Colorado River: Miscellaneous Material on the "Controversy." (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Colorado River: Upper Colorado River. 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Colorado River: All-American Canal Conference. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Central Arizona Project: Bills, Speeches. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Central Arizona Project: Hearings in Congress. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Central Arizona Project: Verde River Irrigation and Power District. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Central Arizona Project: Publications Against. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Central Arizona Project: Miscellaneous Reference Material. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Central Arizona Project: Bridge Canyon Photographs. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gila River Project. 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Water Projects. (Box 2, Folder 12)